<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Nam Tran</title>
    <link>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Nam Tran</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://omn0mn0m.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jarvis</title>
      <link>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/projects/jarvis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/projects/jarvis/</guid>
      <description>JARVIS Repository for past JARVIS attempts and any future tries.
Dependencies  Python 2.7 SpeechRecognition pyttsx PyAudio ChatterBot
Optional Dependencies MongoDB
Past Attempts This project first started at a PennApps hackathon in late 2013 where the code was written in basically two hours with minimal functionality.
  After that, I revisited it in summer 2014 until spring 2015 for my high school graduation project. This time the emphasise was on conversationalism and the ability to answer messages on Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacki Hacki Hackital Club</title>
      <link>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/projects/hacki-hacki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/projects/hacki-hacki/</guid>
      <description>Hacki-Hacki This is a visual novel created as a demo for Hackital 2017, an MLH hackathon that took place at GWU in Washington, DC. You can view the Devpost here.
The game was created by the following people: - Nam Tran - Developer, Writer, Background Photos - Sebastian Foubert - Developer - Brandon Waller - Writer, Character Artist - Adrian Haber - Project Manager
You can download the game to try now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 FRC Robot</title>
      <link>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/projects/robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/projects/robot/</guid>
      <description>FRC-2015 Software for the 2015 FRC robot, written by the Team 708 software team in Java.
##Subsystems - Drivetrain - Vision Processor - Claw and Claw Elevator (same mechanical subsystem, treated as two separate ones in software) - Indexer (also known as tote elevator) - Intake
##Wiring See this Google Spreadsheet
##Significant New Features - Hatter Drive, which is just ChezyDrive with the namespace for anything interesting and original that we may add in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>