<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nam Tran</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nam Tran</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 21:44:46 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>/blog/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 21:44:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>This is that obligatory hello world post that always comes with any sort of programming adventure. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to reboot this website since the last time anything done with it was high school.
This is also my second attempt at a blog. Eventually, I am going to port over the blog posts from my original wordpress I tried to make last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 13:23:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>I am available as a freelance developer if you need code for a project. I am also available to answer technical questions and give advice for free though!
If you have any desire to contact me, you can email me at the giant email address below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 13:19:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a junior studying biomedical engineering at The George Washington University. My plans for the future have yet to be decided on&amp;hellip;
Some of my areas of interest include embedded control systems, digital design, artificial intelligence, and video game design. I have worked on multiple projects in each of these subject areas, and am constantly keeping tabs on the latest tech developments.
I was previously control systems lead for my college&amp;rsquo;s robotics team, and am now co-president of the team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>