<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>privacy on Nam Tran</title>
    <link>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in privacy on Nam Tran</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 04:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://omn0mn0m.github.io/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Chains #4 - Annoying my Friends About Switching to Signal</title>
      <link>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/blog/breaking-the-chains-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/blog/breaking-the-chains-4/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Download Signal as your texting/messaging app because Big Brother is watching you. Or something like that.
Story Time For the first time ever in my life, I wore a literal tin foil hat. Let me take it back a few steps though, and tell you just what led up to this pivotal moment of my life where I became one of the crazies.
An Experiment Last week, I walked into my housemate&amp;rsquo;s room for my weekly attempt to get him to use Signal, a messaging app that uses end-to-end encryption (message is scrambled as it travels from one phone to another, only being unscrambled on the app) when talking to other Signal users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Chains #3 - Taking Care of Your Online Accounts</title>
      <link>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/blog/breaking-the-chains-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/blog/breaking-the-chains-3/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Delete old accounts. Use a password manager to generate new passwords for the accounts you keep. Turn on two-factor authentication. If you really don&amp;rsquo;t care enough to secure your accounts, email me your account details (Don&amp;rsquo;t actually do this. It&amp;rsquo;s illegal).
I got my first email address, tranngocnam97@yahoo.com, in 2011 when I bought Minecraft Alpha. Nearly a decade later, I decided it was finally time to retire the email.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Chains #2 - Why I Chose Firefox Back in 2011 (and Stayed)</title>
      <link>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/blog/breaking-the-chains-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/blog/breaking-the-chains-2/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr Switch to Firefox instead of whatever other web browser you&amp;rsquo;re using.
One of the darkest secrets I am willing to admit is that I used Internet Explorer until my sophomore year of high school. I was still using the family computer to do schoolwork at the time, and like many family computers, it was heavily guarded by my parents. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t allowed to install anything onto it. This was the case until I joined my high school robotics team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Chains #1 - An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/blog/breaking-the-chains-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 14:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://omn0mn0m.github.io/blog/breaking-the-chains-1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Just because you&amp;rsquo;re paranoid doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean they aren&amp;rsquo;t after you.&amp;rdquo;
- Joseph Heller, Catch-22
 My New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolution for 2020 is to break the chains that have been cast upon us by tech companies. This means switching from closed, proprietary software to free and open-source software (FOSS) when possible. It also means being more mindful of who has my personal data, as well as being in as much control over my information as I can be.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>